Register of the Valerian Ivanovich Moravskii Papers, 1917-1937.
Hoover Institution Archives
Valerian Ivanovich Moravskii Papers
1917-1937
48009
Hoover Institution Archives
13 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 2 envelopes (7 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, resolutions, proclamations, financial and legal records, and photographs, relating to the Russian Civil War in Siberia, the anti-Bolshevik Siberian governments of 1918-1922, the Council of Plenipotentiary Representatives of Organizations of Autonomous Siberia, political activities of White Russian emigres in the Far East and elsewhere, and Russian emigre-Japanese relations.
Moravskii, Valerian Ivanovich, 1884-1940
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1948.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Explanatory Notes
Throughout this register the following abbreviation is used: C.P.R.O.A.S. for the Council of Plenipotentiary Representatives of the Organizations of Autonomous Siberia, (Sovet Upolnomochennykh Organizatsii Avtonomnoi Sibiri).
Throughout this register correspondence is arranged by writer, and thereunder by addressee.
Biographical Note
1884 Born, Russia
Graduates from a theological seminary in Bessarabia and the Institute of Agronomy in St. Petersburg. Attends the Academy of Oriental Languages in St. Petersburg
1905-1906 Member of Socialist Revolutionary Party
1908-1918 Works on staff of newspaper Rech' as head of Far Eastern section
1914-1915 Works for Ministry of Ways and Communications
1916 Joins Ministry of Agriculture
1917 Appointed head of Ministry of Food Supply in Provisional Government under Kerensky
1917, Dec. Appointed Secretary General of Siberian Provincial Council
1918 Elected State Secretary of Siberian Provincial Duma. Member of the Provisional Government of Autonomous Siberia. Elected to the Council of Plenipotentiary Representatives of the Organizations of Autonomous Siberia
1922 Appointed Minister of Finance and Minister of Trade and Industry in second (non-Bolshevik) Siberian Government
1922 Emigrates to China. Lives in Shanghai and travels extensively in Manchuria and Japan
1925 Elected Vice-President of Council of Plenipotentiary Representatives of the Organizations of Autonomous Siberia
1928 Becomes Acting President of Council of Plenipotentiary Representatives of Autonomous Siberia
1942 Dies, Shanghai, China
Siberia (Provisional Government, 1917-1918); Sovet Upolnomochennykh Organizatsii Avtonomnoi Sibiri.; East Asia.; Japan.; Russia (Federation); Russians in foreign countries.; Russians--East Asia.; Siberia (Russia)--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union.
- Provisional Government of Siberia, 1918-1922.
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes miscellaneous documents, correspondence, reports and printed material dealing with the period 1918-1920. arranged by physical form.
  - Correspondence. Includes miscellaneous correspondence of P. Derber, Chairman of the Siberian Government and other members of the government re its recognition by foreign powers and the political situation in Siberia, March-July 1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - List of members of the Constituent Assembly, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Printed matter
    - General
      - Nakaz Priamurskomu Narodnomu Sobraniiu, Izdanie Narodnogo Sobraniia, 1922. Pamphlet (Folder 3)
      - Ob avtonomii Sibiri, Irkutsk, 1917 (?). Anonymous pamphlet (Folder 4)
      - Stenograficheskii otchet peregovorov o sdache vlasti Omskim Pravitel'stvom Politicheskomu Tsentru, "Trudovoe T.vo," Harbin, 1921. Pamphlet (Folder 5)
    - Excerpts
      - Graves, W., America's Siberian Adventure, 1918-1920, Jonathan Cape and Harrison Smith, New York, p. 191 (Folder 6)
      - Potanin, G.N., address to the Siberian people. Excerpt from an unidentified newspaper, n.d. (Folder 7)
    - Newspapers (Folder 8)
      - Edinaia Rossiia, No. 6, n.d.
      - Irtysh, No. 35, Oct. 1919
      - Kazach'e Ekho, No. 83, July, 1920
      - Krestianskaia Gazeta, No. 4 and 19, June 1920-Sept.1920
      - Obozrenie, No. 10, Sept. 1920
      - Nashe Slovo, No. 14, Oct. 1920
      - Russkoe Delo, No. 10, Oct. 1919
      - Sibirskaia Rech', No. 226, Oct. 1919
      - Sibirskii Kazak, No. 15, 27, 29, Sept.-Oct. 1919
      - Slovo iz Armii, No. 15, 48, 55, Sept., Nov., Dec. 1920
      - Zabaikal'slaia Nov', No. 3552 and 3557, Sept.-Oct. 1920
  - Proclamations and declarations
    - Miscellaneous proclamations of the Plenipotentiaries of the Siberian Provisional Government, June-Nov. 1918 (Folder 9)
    - Declaration of the Cooperative Bureau of Harbin to the Provisional Maritime Government. Signed A.V. Sazonov, June 1921 (Folder 10)
    - "Deklaratsiia Sibirkago Pravitel'stva". Signed A.V. Sazonov, M.P. Golovachev and G.I. Chertkov, Oct. 1922 (Folder 11)
  - Reports
    - Miscellaneous reports to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, (Provisional Government of Siberia), Aug.-Sept. 1918 (Folder 12)
    - Report re unlawful activities of Ataman Kalmykov, Sept. 1918 (Folder 13)
    - Report on violations of law by Japanese authorities in Vladivostok, Sept. 1918
- Civil War, 1920-1932.
  Documents, correspondence and excerpts from printed material dealing with anti-Communist military forces and their relations with the Council of Plenipotentiary Representatives of the Organizations of Autonomous Siberia. Includes material on Lt. Gen. Ataman G.M. Semenov, Lt. Gen. A.N. Pepeliaev and other generals representing the Cossack armies of Siberia. Arranged by physical form.
  - Lt. Gen. G.M. Semenov (Box 1)
    - Agreement with C.P.R.O.A.S. Arranged chronologically
      - Decree of Admiral Kolchak transferring civil and military authority to Lt. Gen. G.M. Semenov, Jan. 1920. (English translation) (Folder 14)
      - Protocol of meeting between Lt. Gen. G.M. Semenov, M.P. Golovachev and V.I. Moravskii, Nov. 1922 (Folder 15)
      - Legal agreement between Lt. Gen. G.M. Semenov and C.P.R.O.A.S., Feb. 7, 1922. (Includes French and English translation) (Folder 16)
      - Supplementary agreement, n.d.
      - Testimony of Lt. Gen. G.M. Semenov re agreement of Feb. 1922, Feb. 1926 (Folder 17)
      - Confirmation of agreement of Feb. 1922, signed by G.M. Semenov, V.I. Moravskii and A.V. Sazonov, June 1926 (Folder 18)
      - Deposition of A.V. Sazonov re agreement of Feb. 1922, n.d. (Folder 19)
      - "Obrashchenie k Sibirskomu Pravitel'stvu," signed Lt. Gen. Ataman Semenov, n.d. (Folder 20)
    - Correspondence
      - C.P.R.O.A.S. (Folder 2l)
        - Semenov, G.M., Feb. 1922
      - Semenov, G.M.
        - Agapov, E.M., (telegrams), 1922 (Folder 22)
        - Balakin, A.V., Nov. 1921-Oct. 1932 (Folder 23)
        - Moravskii, V.I., Aug. 1922- Apr. 1927 (Folder 24)
        - Sazonov, A.V., Oct. 1922 (Folder 25)
    - Writings. "Appeal to the American People," (a brief history of his anti-Bolshevik campaign, 1917-1922), 1922 (Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Agapov, E.M., letter re activities of "Semenovtsy" in Shanghai, May 1924 (Folder 27)
      - Cherednichenko-Mersie, V.P., report to G.M. Semenov, Nov. 1927 (Folder 28)
      - Longov, "Izmena belogo lidera Atamana Semenova i polozhenie priniatoe Mukdenskoi Partiei," (document confiscated during search of Soviet Embassy in Peking), Nov. 1927 (Folder 29)
      - Resolution of the Former Commander-in-Chief of the Far Eastern Army, n.d. (Folder 30)
      - Russkoe Slovo, "Razoblachenie Besedovskago," Harbin, n.d. (Re Soviet connection of G.M. Semenov) (Folder 31)
      - Sosnovskii, A.S. (Folder 32)
        - Semenov, G.M., (report re Gen. Glebov), n.d.
  - C.P.R.O.A.S. and military forces in the Far East
    - Lt. Gen. A.N. Pepeliaev
      - Correspondence with A.V. Sazonov, May 1921-Aug. 1922, (includes letter of N.I. Pepeliaeva, wife of A.N. Pepeliaev, to A.V. Sazonov) (Folder 33)
      - Printed material. "Delo Generala Pepeliaeva," Zarubezhnaia Rus', No. 70, Shanghai, Feb. 9, 1922 (Folder 34)
    - Military groups and others recognizing the C.P.R.O.A.S. as the government of Siberia. Arranged chronologically
      - Tsentral'naia Gruppa Voennoi Organizatsii Narrevarmii, Jan. 1922 (Folder 35)
      - Nachal'nik Shtaba Komanduiushchago Sibirskoi Flotiliei, June 1922 (Folder 36)
      - Prikaz vsem russkim sukhoputmym voiskam territorii Priamurskago Pravitel'stva, June 1922 (Folder 37)
      - Delegatsiia Vremennago IAkutskago Oblastnogo Narodnago Upravleniia, Sept. 1922 (Folder 38)
      - Representatives of the Cossack Armies of Siberia, Baksheev, Ataman Zabaikal Cossack Army, Ivanov-Rynov, Lt. Gen. Siberian Cossack Army, Korenev,Ataman Amur Cossack Army, Ogloblin, Ataman Irkutsk Cossack Army, Sept. 1922 (Folder 39)
      - Lebedev, Maj. Gen.
        - Prikaz po sukhoputnym voiskam na pol. ostr. Muraviev-Amurs, Oct. 1922 (Folder 40)
        - Letter to A.V. Sazonov, Nov. 1922 (Folder 41)
      - Resolution of the Ural and Eger' Regiments, Sept. 1923 (Folder 42)
- Council of the Plenipotentiary Representatives of the Organizations of Autonomous Siberia, (C.P.R.O.A.S.), 1917-1934
  Miscellaneous material of the Council of the PLenipotentiary Representatives of the Organizations of Autonomous Siberia. Includes correspondence and reports of affiliated sections; material re activity of intelligence section; miscellaneous reports, especially about Siberia; biographical material and personal documents of its members; memoranda, resolutions and protocols of meetings. Arranged by physical form.
  - General
    - List of C.P.R.O.A.S. representatives abroad, n.d. (Folder 43)
    - Powers of attorney and letters of instruction issued by C.P.R.O.A.S., Feb. 1922-Apr. 1934 (Folder 44)
  - Affiliated sections of C.P.R.O.A.S.
    - Byelorussian Section. Protocol of C.P.R.O.A.S. meeting with Siberians from Byelorussia, Dec. 1932 (Folder 45)
    - Canadian Section
      - Miscellaneous materials, (includes correspondence of C.P.R.O.A.S. with G.N. Popov and IU.K. Poppel), 1919-1932 (Folder 46)
      - Report from C.P.R.O.A.S. to G.N. Popov, Sept. 1930 (Folder 47)
    - Far Eastern Group of C.P.R.O.A.S.
      - Protocol of meeting, Dec. 1932 (Folder 48)
      - Miscellaneous material, (includes letter from V.I. Moravskii), Aug. 1932
    - Harbin Section
      - Letter to C.P.R.O.A.S., Feb. 1931 (Folder 49)
      - Letter from V.I. Moravskii to I.A. Aliadvin, (chairman of the Harbin Section), Aug. 1930
    - Moslem Section. Miscellaneous material, includes resolutions, reports, correspondence, speeches, 1921-1932 (Folder 50)
    - Ukrainian Section. Protocol of C.P.R.O.A.S. meeting with Siberians from the Ukraine, Oct. 1932 (Folder 51)
  - Budget of C.P.R.O.A.S., Oct.-Nov. 1923 (Folder 52)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - C.P.R.O.A.S.
        - Invitation to conference, Oct. 1930 (Folder 53)
        - Letter to its members, Sept. 1930
        - Telegrams
          - Great Northern Telegraph Co., 1923-1934 (Folder 54)
          - Imperial Japanese Telegraphs, 1923-1929 (Folder 55)
          - Miscellaneous, mostly undated (Folder 56)
      - Military training. Includes correspondence of V.I.Moravskii, V.V. Bretenar and list of volunteers from Harbin, Aug.-Dec. 1932 (Folder 57)
      - Moravskii, V.I. Official letters to members of C.P.R.O.A.S., Feb.-March 1927 (Folder 58)
      - Russian residents of Shanghai. Letter to C.P.R.O.A.S., Jan. 1927 (Folder 59)
    - Organizations (Box 2)
      - C.P.R.O.A.S.
        - Liga po bor'be s Tret'em Internatsionalom, Oct. 1926-Feb. 1927 (Folder 1)
        - Liga Z.Z.P.P., (Liga Zakonomernoi Zashchity Pravovogo Poriadka), Nov. 1926 (Folder 2)
        - Liga Zashchity Konstitutsii v Shankhae, nd. (Folder 3)
        - Moskovkaia Demokraticheskaia Gruppa, n.d. (Folder 4)
        - Russian Anti-Communist Committee of IAkutsk, Kamchatka and Sakhalin, letter to C.P.R.O.A.S., Oct. 1930 (Folder 5)
        - Soiuz Mladorosov na Dal'nem Vostoke, letter to V.I. Moravskii, n.d. (Folder 6)
        - Vserossiiskii Krestianskii Soiuz, letter to V.I. Moravskii, March 1932 (Folder 7)
    - Resettlement of Siberian refugees abroad
      - C.P.R.O.A.S., letter to British Ambassador in Tokyo re resettlement in Canada, n.d. (Folder 8)
      - Poppel, IU., letter to S.V. Levchatkin-Atkins re resettlement in Mexico, June, 1934 (Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous material re resettlement in Alaska, n.d (Folder 10)
  - Intelligence
    - Codes and ciphers. Lists of codes and ciphers used by C.P.R.O.A.S. and its agents, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - Correspondence
      - Letters from "Aleksandr," "Fedia i Misha," "Vasilii," Jan. 1932 (Folder 12)
      - Nikiforov (Folder 13)
        - M.P. Golovachev, Feb. 1927
      - Nikole de Shole (Folder 14)
        - V.I. Moravskii, March 1927- March 1928
    - Diagrams,n.d
      - Bolshevik influence in Mukden (Folder 15)
      - Intelligence network of the Kamchatka Regional Committee
    - Reports to Information Section. Arranged chronologically
      - Weekly reports re activity of Soviet Embassy, Aug.-Dec. 1925 (Folder 16)
      - "Dislokatsiia voisk v Zabaikalie," 1926 (Folder 17)
      - Coded messages, 1928 (Folder 18)
      - Weekly reports re Soviet activity, 1929 (Folder 19)
      - Report re troops in Ekaterino-Nikol'sk, June 1929 (Folder 20)
      - Report re arrest of Gen. Tiptsov and Zagoskin by Chinese authorities, 1930 (Folder 21)
      - Report re the Polish Siberian connection, 1931 (Folder 22)
      - Reports, 1932 (Folder 23)
        - Borisov, M.
        - Sokolov, N.
      - Miscellaneous material, 1933 (Folder 24)
    - Reports, miscellaneous
      - Bretenar, V.V. to V.I. Moravskii, Nov. 1931 (Folder 25)
      - Vasiliev-Dubrovskii, June 1928 (Folder 26)
      - Letter of instruction from C.P.R.O.A.S. to I.Kaplin, March 1923 (Folder 27)
      - List of German advisers in Nankin, n.d. (Folder 28)
      - Report to Gen. R. Gaida re establishment of intelligence network on Soviet territory, n.d. (Folder 29)
      - Report re internal situation in emigre political circles, n.d. (Folder 30)
      - Report re popular mood in Siberia and anti-Soviet activity of the masses, n.d. (Folder 31)
  - Memoranda and resolutions
    - "Polozhenie o Sovete Upolnomochennykh Organizatsii Avtonomnoi Sibiri". Draft and typescript copy, 1924 (Folder 32)
    - "Polozhenie o vremennom voennom otdele pri Sovete Upolnomochennykh po kazach'im delam". Draft, 1922 (Folder 33)
    - "Prikaz C.P.R.O.A.S.," n.d. (Folder 34)
    - "Proekt nelegal'noi voenoi organizatsii Sibiri". Miscellaneous material, 1923 (Folder 35)
    - Brief history of Siberian government and C.P.R.O.A.S., n.d. (Folder 36)
    - Memorandum re history and purpose of C.P.R.O.A.S. Draft, n.d. (Folder 37)
    - Sazonov, A.V. The tasks of the Siberian government, n.d. (Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous memoranda re situation in Siberia, n.d. (Folder 39)
    - Diagram of structure of C.P.R.O.A.S., n.d. (Folder 40)
  - Personal documents and biographical material
    - Borisov, M.I. Short biography compiled for C.P.R.O.A.S., Aug. 1932 (Folder 41)
    - Chertkov, G.I. Report re his arrest and incarceration by the Japanese, March, 1933 (Folder 42)
    - Gard-Douglas, J.K. Newspaper clippings, 1931-1932 (Folder 43)
    - Lavrov, I.IA. Miscellaneous material, Nov. 1933 (Folder 44)
    - Levchatkin-Atkins, S.V. Short biography, letter of identification, Feb. 1920 (Folder 45)
    - Moravskii, V.I. Photocopies of personal documents, including passport, letters of identification, letters of instruction and powers of attorney, 1917-1925 (Folder 46)
    - Purin, A.A. Short biography and letter of exclusion from C.P.R.O.A.S., 1928-1931 (Folder 47)
    - Sazonov, A.V. Personal documents, including passports, letters of identification, membership cards, Sept. 1919-Feb. 1925 (Folder 48)
  - Proclamations and declarations
    - "Biulleten' S.U.O.A.S.," special edition, June 1922 (Folder 49)
    - "Bor'ba za avtonomnuiu Sibir'". Declaration to foreign powers, 1931 (Folder 50)
    - "Deklaratsiia Sibirkago Pravitel'stva," Jan. 1923 (Folder 51)
    - Proclamation to workers. Draft, 1928 (?) (Folder 52)
  - Protocols of meetings
    - n.d. (Folder 53)
    - 1922 (Folder 54)
    - 1923 (Folder 55)
    - 1927 (Folder 56)
    - 1934 (Folder 57)
  - Publishing
    - Contracts
      - P.P. Malykh, V.I. Moravskii, A.V. Sazonov and L.F. Lundstrom to establish publishing firm, "Democratic Press," Harbin, May 1921 (Folder 58)
      - V.I. Moravskii, G.I. Chertkov, S.I. Zenkevich and R.D. Babushkin-Rafalov to establish "Siberian Publishing Firm," Shanghai, May 1928 (Folder 59)
    - Nasha Gazetta. Censor's orders. Jan.-May, 1933 (Folder 60)
    - Miscellaneous material, n.d. (Folder 61)
  - Reports to C.P.R.O.A.S. (Box 3)
    - Siberia and the Far East
      - "Aliaska i Kamchatka v svete griadushchikh sobytii," n.d. (Folder 1)
      - "Nekotoryia soobrazheniia kasatel'no vozstanovleniia svobodnoi Sibiri," n.d. (Folder 2)
      - "Obshchee polozhenie v russkikh oblastiakh Dal'nego Vostoka i v Manchzhurii," n.d. (Folder 3)
      - "Obshchee polozhenie sovetskoi vlasti v Tadzhikistane," 1934 (Folder 4)
      - "Osnovy organizatsii revoliutsionnogo dvizheniia i politicheskogo perevorota v Ussuriiskom Krae," n.d. (Folder 5)
      - "Polozhenie v IAkutskoi Oblasti," Nov. 1930 (Folder 6)
      - "Sibir'," n.d. (Folder 7)
      - "Zabaikalie, nastroenie naseleniia i armii," n.d. (Folder 8)
      - Diagram. Organizational plan of Western group, Sept. 1922 (Folder 9)
      - Report re Manchuria, n.d. (Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous reports re situation in Siberia, n.d. (Folder 11)
      - B.I., (representative of Illegal Organizations of Siberian Autonomists). The situation in Siberia and the work of Siberian organizations, n.d. (Folder 12)
      - Chertkov, G.I., "Bor'ba s bol'shevizmom v Sibiri i Oblastniki," n.d. (Folder 13)
      - M.G. How to separate Siberia from the rest of the Soviet Union, n.d. (Folder 14)
      - M.I. Report re his trip to the Maritime Provinces, Nov. 1931 (Folder 15)
      - N.S.K. Explanatory note, n.d. (Folder 16)
      - Russian, V.N.
        - The Omsk Government in 1918-1919, n.d. (Folder 17)
        - Notes on the situation in Omsk, n.d.
        - Report re the execution of three Americans, June 1920 (Folder 18)
    - Military
      - "Dokladnaiia zapiska S.U.O.A.S. ob organizatsii bor'by s sovetskoi vlast'iu za osvobozhdenie Sibiri," n.d. (Folder 19)
      - "Organizatsiia privlecheniia sil k aktivnoi rabote," n.d. (Folder 20)
      - "Pamiatnaia zapiska". Organization of expedition into Chinese Turkestan, 1934 (Folder 21)
      - "Poiasnitel'naia zapiska i kratkaia instruktsiia k proektu organizatsii partizanskikh otriadov v Priamurie," n.d. (Folder 22)
      - "Soobrazheniia k voprosu A.B.C.," n.d. (Folder 23)
      - "Vooruzhennyia sily S.S.S.R. na Dal'nem Vostoke," 1934 (Folder 24)
      - "Vostochnaia Baza," n.d. (Folder 25)
      - "Zadacha raboty," n.d. (Folder 26)
      - A.D., "Po voennoi i voienno-morskoi chasti," n.d. (Folder 27)
      - A.V. The organizatin of military action, n.d. (Folder 28)
      - Golovachev, M.P., plan for military action in Kamchatka, n.d. (Folder 29)
      - Sibirskaia Boevaia Organizatsiia. Report, n.d. (Folder 30)
    - Technical Section, report re structure of technical section, Nov. 1932 (Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous. n.d.
      - "Chto nuzhno russkim v Manchzhurii" (Folder 32)
      - "Mysli o grazhdanskoi voine v usloviakh nashego vremeni" (Folder 33)
      - A.V., "Torgovo-promyshlennyii kontrol'" (Folder 34)
      - Russian, V.N., "Rabota okhrannykh otdelenii v Rossii" (Folder 35)
- Relations with China, Czechoslovakia and Japan, 1921-1936
  Material re relations of the Russian emigre community in the Far East with China, Czechoslovakia and Japan. Includes treaties and agreements with Chinese and Japanese authorities, reports, maps, printed matter and correspondence. Arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - China (Box 4)
    - Reports
      - "Razvitie bol'shevitskago dvizheniia v Kitae," n.d. (Folder l)
      - "S.M.K. ili Severo-Manchzhurskii Komitet V.K.P.(b)," n.d. (Folder 2)
      - "Zakliuchenie sekretnogo torgovogo dogovora pravitel'stva Sinkianga s S.S.S.R.," Oct. 1931 (Folder 3)
      - Russian, V.N., "Rabota Tretiego Internatsionala v Kitae,"n.d. (Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous reports, n.d. (Folder 5)
    - Treaties
      - Chan Su-chan, Marshal and G.M. Semenov, Gen., n.d. (Folder 6)
      - Chang Tso-lin, Marshal and C.P.R.O.A.S. Draft, n.d. (Folder 7)
      - U Pei-fu, Marshal and G. M. Semenov, Gen.
        - Declaration of Marshal U Pei-fu, Oct. 1924 (Folder 8)
        - Preliminary negotiations, n.d. (Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Diagram and map illustrating Communist infiltration in China. Photocopies, n.d. (Folder 10)
      - Form letter protesting return of Russian refugees by Chinese authorities, n.d. (Folder 11)
      - Map of Tannu-Ola region. Photocopy, n.d. (Folder 12)
      - "Ob"iavlenie politseiskago upravleniia Osobago Raiona Vostochnykh Provintsii," Jan. 1921 (Folder l3)
  - Czechoslovakia
    - Printed matter
      - Vestnik, "Sobytiia v Vostochnoi Azii i bor'ba za osvobozhdenie Rossii," Prague. Typescript excerpt, n.d. (Folder 14)
      - Vseslavianskii Komitet Pomoshchi Russkomu Narodu ("Liga"), "Neskol'ko dannykh i dokumentov, kasaiushchikhsia Dal'ne-Vostochnykh sobytii i nazrevaiushchei tam bor'by za osvobozhdenie Rossii," Prague, 1932 (Folder 15)
    - Correspondence
      - Bretenar, V.V.
        - Domracheev, M.I., Oct. 1931 (Folder 16)
        - Gaida, R., n.d. (Folder 17)
        - Moravskii, V.I., Jan. 1931-Aug. 1932 (Folder 18)
      - Czechoslovak Consulate, Shanghai (Folder 19)
        - Moravskii, V.I., Nov. 1931
      - Domracheev, M. IA. (Folder 20)
        - Bretenar, V.V., Oct-Nov. 1931
      - E.L.KH., Feb. 1932 (Folder 21)
        - Gaida, R., Feb. 1932
      - Gaida, R.
        - Bretenar, V.V., Nov. 1930-Apr. 1931 (Folder 22)
        - Far Eastern Emigration,address, Apr. 1931 (Folder 23)
        - Moravskii, V.I., Apr. 1931 (Folder 24)
      - Group 65 (Folder 25)
        - Kramarz, K., Nov. 1931
      - IAkushev, I.A. (Folder 26)
        - A.V. Sazonov, Nov. 1926
      - KHorvat, D.L.
        - Danilevskii, Oct. 1930 (Folder 27)
        - Glavacek, Oct. 1930
        - Kramarz, K., Oct. 1930
        - Vladislavtsev, I.A., Aug. 1931 (Folder 28)
      - Moravskii, V.I.
        - Bretenar, V.V., Aug. 1930-June 1936 (Folder 29)
        - Gaida, R., n.d. (Folder 30)
        - Halla, Karel, (Czechoslovak Ambassador to Tokyo), n.d. (Folder 31)
        - Heine, R.F., (Czechoslovak Consul in Harbin), 1932 (Folder 32)
        - Kramarz, K., n.d. (Folder 33)
        - Vitkovskii, P., n.d. (Folder 34)
      - Rusky Zahranicni Historicky Archiv (Folder 35)
        - Levchatkin-Atkins, S.V., Feb. 1933
      - S. (Folder 36)
        - Gaida, R., April, 1932
      - Vladislavtsev, I.A. (Folder 37)
        - Bretenar, V.V., June-Apr. 1932
        - Moravskii, V.I., Aug. 1931
      - Zalozna Slovanska Vzajemnost' v Praze (Folder 38)
        - V.I. Moravskii, Aug. 1931
    - Miscellaneous. Letter of instruction and power of attorney from C.P.R.O.A.S. to V.V. Bretenar, Feb. 1931 (Folder 39)